A Guide to the Riddick Family Papers, 1720-1856
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Papers, 1720-1856
Library of Virginia
23846
.15 cubic feet
Riddick Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Do not serve originals. Serve photostat copies.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sue Wingfield Riddick, Suffolk, Virginia, 1952.
Biographical Information
The Riddick family was a prominent family in Nansemond County and Suffolk, Virginia. The Riddicks owned extensive property in the county and town and intermarried with other prominent families of Nansemond County including the Norfleets and Prentises. Moses Riddick (ca. 1715-1799) was the father of Jethro Riddick (ca. 1741-1799). Jethro was the father of Edward Riddick (1765-1849) who married Ann "Nancy" Goodman (1782-1855). They had 3 children, including Jethro Riddick (1803-1874) who married Elizabeth Vaughan (1806-1880). Their daughter Mary Ann Riddick (1831-1871) married Willis Smith Riddick (1818-1875). Thomas Fiveash Riddick (1781-1830) was the grandson of Moses Riddick through his son Jason Riddick (d. 1785).
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1720-1856, of the Riddick family of Nansemond County, Virginia, consisting of bills of sale, deeds, judicial records, plats, and wills. Deeds and plats cover lands purchased in Nansemond County, and one deed for land purchased in Camden, North Carolina. Wills are of members of the Riddick family. Bill of sale is for a male slave purchased by Abraham Riddick. Bond is for losses in purchase of part of Old Lebanon Swamp. Judicial record is a bill of complaint in suit of Thomas Fiveash Riddick vs. Jethro Riddick's executor. Serve photostat copies, not originals.
Arrangement
chronological
Contents List
- Deed, 25 September 1720, for 100 acres in Nansemond County, Virginia, from Terlak Oquin to Humphrey Griffin, both of Nansemond County., a; 1 leaf, photostat.
- Deed, 22 November 1739, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from John Duke to Richard Newsam, both of Nansemond County., b; 3 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 9 April 1748 and recorded 11 April 1748, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Jotham Lassiter to Moses Riddick, both of Nansemond County., c; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Will, 29 January 1752, of Joan Riddick of Nansemond County., d; 1 leaf, photostat.
- Deed, 7 December 1755 and recorded 12 January 1756, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Humphrey Griffin to Thomas Harrell, both of Nansemond County., e; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 15 September 1762 and recorded 11 October 1762, for 125 acres in Nansemond County from Christopher Giwin to Moses Riddick, both of Nansemond County., f; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 12 March 1770 and recorded 9 April 1770, for 147 acres in Nansemond County from Thomas Jennings of Elizabeth City County, Virginia, to Jethro Riddick of Nansemond County., g; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 22 February 1800 and recorded 14 July 1800, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Hezekiah Norfleet to John Norfleet, both of Nansemond County., h; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 9 September 1802 and recorded 13 September 1802, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Thomas and Martha Harrell to Edward Riddick, all of Nansemond County., i; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 22 October 1804 and recorded 10 June 1805, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from John Norfleet to Edward R. Cunningham, both of Nansemond County., j; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Plat, 29 December 1807, of 353 acres of land in Nansemond County resurveyed for Daniel Duke, Solomon Creech, and William Woodward., k; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 1808 and recorded 11 January 1808, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Daniel and Chirstian Duke of Gates County, North Carolina, William and Sarah Woodward adn Pleasant Spivey, widow of Joshua Spivey, all of Nansemond County to Edward Riddick of Nansemond County., m; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Plat, 9 March 1808, of 79 acres in Nansemond County resurveyed for Arthur Jones., n; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed of gift, 17 February 1810 and recorded 14 May 1810, from Abraham Harrell to Benjamin Harrell, both of Nansemond County., o; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 1 January 1811 and recorded 11 March 1811, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Miles Ellis to Jesse Griffin, both of Nansemond County., p; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 28 January 1811 and recorded 11 February 1811, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Elisha and Martha Norfleet to Edward Riddick, all of Nansemond County., q; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 18 January 1812 and recorded 13 July 1812, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Washington Smith and Samuel R. Cunningham to Edward Riddick, all of Nansemond County., r; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Plat, 7 April 1815, for 96 acres in Nansemond County resurveyed for Edward Riddick., s; 1 leaf, photostat.
- Deed, 25 June 1830 and recorded 3 December 1831, for tracts of land in Nansemond County from Edward and Nacy Riddick to Jethro Riddick, all of Nansemond County., t; 5 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 9 September 1830 and recorded 23 October 1830, for 32 acres in Nansemond County from Demsey Jones to Jethro Riddick, both of Nansemond County., u; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 27 November 1830 and recorded 27 November 1830, for 57 acres in Nansemond County from Demsey Jones to Norfleet Jones, both of Nansemond County., v; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Plat, 11 August 1832, for 19 1/4 acres in Nansemond County surveyed for Jethro Riddick., w; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 13 February 1833 and recorded 13 February 1833, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from William Griffin to Jethro Riddick, both of Nansemond County., x; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 11 February 1833 and recorded 23 March 1833, for a tract of land in Nansemond County from Norfleet Jones to Jethro Riddick, both of Nansemond County., y; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 30 December 1833 and recorded 21 August 1834, for two tracts of land in Nansemond County from Edward and Nancy Riddick to Jethro Riddick, all of Nansemond County., z; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Bill of sale, 13 June 1834, for a male slave from Benjamin Brinkley of Gates County, North Carolina, to Abraham Riddick, Sr., of Nansemond County., aa; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Bond, 16 April 1842, of John B. Benton, Thomas G. Benton, and James B. Norfleet indemnifying the losses of Edward and Jethro Riddick in the purchase of part of Old Lebanon Swamp., bb; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 14 April 1843 and recorded 13 May 1843, for two tracts of land in Nansemond County from Nancy Griffin, widow of Miles Griffin, and Brinkley Griffin to Jethro Riddick, all of Nansemond County., cc; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 19 November 1853 and recorded 20 December 1853, for 120 acres in Nansemond County from Willis S. Riddick, trustee of Sarah I. Smith, to Jethro Riddick, all of Nansemond County., dd; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Deed, 1 January 1856, for 396 acres in Camden, North Carolina, from Abram and Nancy Brinkley to Jethro Riddick, all of Nansemond County., ee; 2 leaves, photostats.
- Bill of complaint, n.d., in Thomas Fiveash Riddick vs. Jethro Riddick's executor in Nansemond chancery court., ff; 4 leaves, photostats.
- Plat, n.d., for 81 acres in Nansemond County for Jethro Riddick., gg; 2 leaves, photostats.